War Posters Collection
War Posters Collection
- World War I
  - First In The Fight – Always Faithful / Be A US Marine!, undated; WWI-61; 107cm / 71.5cm red, white, blue, Marine in Uniform (Map-case 52)
    Condition: Tears along all four sides
  - US Marines Active Service on Land & Sea / Enlist at 8 Fourth Ave. Brooklyn, undated; WWI-62; 101cm / 72cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Soldier with a gun marching in front of battleship
    Condition: Large tears on left and right sides
  - On Guard! It's A Pretty Big Job For One Bird! / Join the Navy! Apply Recruiting Station or Navy League, Feb. 1917; WWI-63; 63.5cm / 46.5cm black, white (Map-case 52)
    Type: U.S. Navy
    Description: American Eagle overlooking river with battleship
    Artist: HB Matthews
  - Gee! I Wish I Were A Man, I'd Join The Navy / Be A Man And Do It, 1917; WWI-64; 104.5cm / 68cm red, white, blue, black (Map-case 52)
    Description: Woman dressed in a Navy uniform
    Artist: Howard Chandler Christy
    Condition: Tears along all four edges, some discoloration
  - All Together! Enlist In the Navy, 1917; WWI-65; 109.5cm / 80cm multi (Map-case 52)
    Description: Sailors from Italy, Belgium, Australia, USA, France, & Japan
    Artist: H. Reuterdahl U.S.N.R.F.
    Condition: Several damaged areas around the sides
  - Will you supply eyes for the Navy? Navy ships need binoculars & spy-glasses /, undated; WWI-66; 74cm / 52cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Captain blindfolded on a ship - Naval Observatory
    Artist: Gordon Grant
    Printer: Sackett & Wilhelm Corp., New York
  - A Wonderful Opportunity for You U.S. Navy, undated; WWI-67; 71cm / 52 cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Sailor on leave, ashore
    Artist: Ruttan
    Condition: Damage on corners, some small tears
  - Sword is Drawn The Navy Upholds It! / US Navy Recruiting Station, 34 East 23rd Street, NYC, undated; WWI-68; 106.5cm / 71cm red, white, blue, black (Map-case 52)
    Description: Liberty standing with a drawn sword
    Artist: Kenyon Cox, N.A.
    Condition: Falling apart along the edges, large tear and missing top section, large tears bottom
  - Help Deliver the Goods - Do It Now / US Navy Recruiting Station / Laura & Forsythe Streets, Jacksonville, undated; WWI-69; 104cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 52)
    Description: Sailor hoisting cargo
    Artist: Paus
    Condition: Some fraying along edges
  - Your Country Needs You In the Navy / Enlist Now (addresses of recruiting stations), undated; WWI-70; 52cm / 73.5cm blue, white (Map-case 52)
    Condition: Small tear on right edge – no other damage
  - Navy Men Needed Now, US Navy Recruiting Station, 34 East 23rd St., NYC …, undated; WWI-71; 96.5cm / 64cm black, white (Map-case 52)
    Description: Executive order by Wilson
    Condition: Large tear in bottom portion and tear in upper half
  - Follow the Boys in Blue / For Home & Country / Enlist In The Navy, undated; WWI-72; 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Soldier in line to board a battleship
    Artist: G. Wright
    Printer: Gill Engraving Co. NY
    Condition: Bottom left edge is damaged
  - Navy Needs You! Don't Read American History – Make It! / US Navy Recruiting Station (address), undated; WWI-73; 107cm / 71.5cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Liberty, soldiers, businessman
    Condition: Major tears on all sides, upper right corner missing – VERY DAMAGED
  - Join the Navy The Service For Fighting Men, undated; WWI-74; 107cm / 71.5cm multi (Map-case 52)
    Description: Sailor riding a missile
    Artist: Babcock
    Condition: Tears along edges
  - We Have Met the Enemy & they are ours / The Navy's First U-boat Capture / LAD!, undated; WWI-75; 36cm / 43cm black, white, red (Map-case 52)
    Description: US Navy photo
    Artist: From a photo taken on the USS Fanning
    Printer: Press of US Navy Recruitment Bureau New York
  - Teamwork Wins / U.S. Shipping Board Emergency Fleet Corporation, undated; WWI-76; 105cm / 67 cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: U.S. Shipping Board
    Description: Men & soldiers together repairing
    Artist: Hibberd VB Kline
    Printer: Publications Section, Philadelphia
    Condition: Small tear on top and bottom edges
  - For Every Fighter A Woman Worker / Back Our Second Line of Defense / United War Work Campaign – YWCA, undated; WWI-77; 107cm / 70.5cm blue, orange, yellow, black, white (Map-case 52)
    Type: United War Work Campaign
    Description: Army of women marching
    Artist: Ernest Hamlin Baker
  - For Home & Country / Victory Liberty Loan, 1918; WWI-78; 76.5cm / 505.5cm multi (Map-case 52)
    Type: Victory Liberty Loan
    Description: Soldier holding son, hugging wife
    Artist: Alfred Everitt Orr
  - Americans All! Victory Liberty Loan / Honor Roll, 1919; WWI-79; 102 cm / 68 cm multi (Map-case 52)
    Description: Victory standing in front of American Flag
    Condition: No damage
  - And They Thought We Couldn't Fight!, undated; WWI-80; 106cm / 77.5cm multi (Map-case 52)
    Description: Soldier on battlefield wounded, smile & look of triumph on face
    Artist: Clyde (Vic) Forsythe
    Condition: Tears on various edges
  - Keep the Sea Lanes Open / Invest In the Victory Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-81; 101cm / 74.5cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Submarines & battleships
    Artist: L.A. Shafer
    Condition: Tears along edges, large one on the right side
  - Sure! We'll Finish the Job, 1918; WWI-82; 96.5cm / 66cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: Victory Liberty Union
    Description: Man in overalls & hat
    Artist: Gerrit A. Beneker
    Condition: Small tears around edges
  - Lend the way they Fight, Buy Bonds to your UTMOST, undated; WWI-83; 3 copies 105cm / 69cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: War Bonds
    Description: Soldier throwing a grenade in a trench
    Artist: M. Ache
    Printer: W.F. Powers Co. Litho., NY
    Condition: Copy 1 – Tears around the edges Copies 2&3 – Torn edges held together with tape
  - For Victory, Buy More War Bonds / Fourth Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-84; 133cm / 83cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Figure of Liberty, American eagle
    Artist: J. Scott Williams
    Condition: Large tears, tape along portions of the back, folded in half
  - Save Your Child From Autocracy & Poverty / Buy War Saving Stamps (U.S. Treasury) / War Saving Stamps Issued by the U.S. Government, undated; WWI-85; 102.5cm / 76cm white, brown, yellow, blue, green (Map-case 52)
    Type: War Saving Stamps
    Description: Child standing with the hand from the Statue of Liberty
    Artist: Herbert Paus
    Condition: Tears along the edges
  - They Give Their Lives Do You Lend Your Savings?, undated; WWI-86; 76.5cm / 50.5cm black, blue, yellow, red, white (Map-case 52)
    Description: Hill with cross, gravestones, dark sky
    Artist: H. Druittwelsh
  - Joan of Arc Saved France / Save Your Country – Buy War Saving Stamps / Issued by the U.S. Government, US Treasury Department, undated; WWI-87; 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Joan of Arc holding a Sword
    Artist: Haskell Coffin
    Printer: US Printing & Lithograph Co.
  - For Victory Buy – W.S.S War Saving Stamps, undated; WWI-88; 71.5cm / 50.5cm blue, white, yellow, brown (Map-case 52)
    Description: Soldier holding rifle in battle
    Printer: Rhode Island War Saving Contest
    Condition: Small tear along edges
  - Buy War-Saving Stamps W.S.S. / Stamp Stamp Stamp - The Boys Are Marching / Buy Buy Buy, undated; WWI-89; 71.5cm / 50.5cm white, red, blue (Map-case 52)
    Description: Soldiers marching
    Printer: Rhode Island War Savings Contest
  - YMCA – (cable from Pershing, from France, August 21, 1918), March 1918; WWI-90; 84.5cm / 56cm black, white (Map-case 52)
    Type: YMCA
    Description: Cable from Pershing from France
    Artist: S.J. Wooks - Paris
    Condition: A couple small tears on the edges and not much damage
  - Workers YMCA Lend Your Strength to the red triangle / Help the "Y" help the fighters fight United War Work Campaign – November 11 to 18, undated; WWI-91; 69.5cm / 50cm grey, red, white (Map-case 52)
    Artist: Gil Spear
    Condition: no damage(posters purchased June, 1999)
  - Rien A Faire – sans L'Emprunt Dela Victoire, undated; WWI-92; 90.5cm / 61cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: French
    Description: Scene of a deserted factory in the winter
    Artist: Malcolm Gibson
    Condition: Damaged along the bottom and left edges
  - Keep It Coming. "We must not only feed our soldiers, undated; WWI-93; 76.5cm / 51cm red, white, blue, black, military green (Map-case 52)
    Type: Food Rationing
    Description: Convoy of military food trucks in the winter
    Artist: Illian
    Condition: Some damage along the edges
  - Ships Are Coming – U.S. Shipping Board, Emergency Fleet Corporation, undated; WWI-94; 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: American Bald Eagle flying over military ships
    Artist: James H. Daugherty
    Printer: Forbes, Boston
    Condition: Some tears along the edges, major damage along the bottom
  - Make every Minute Count for Pershing / U.S. Shipping Board, Emergency Fleet Corporation, undated; WWI-95; 72cm / 56cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Man working on a ship, boatyard in the background
    Artist: Adolph Treidler
    Printer: Issued by the Publications Section, Emergency Fleet Corporation, Philadelphia
    Condition: minor tears along the edges
  - Woman's Land Army of America – Women enlist now & help the Farmer Fight the Food Famine, 1918; WWI-96; 77cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: Woman's Land Army of America
    Description: Female army of farm workers, one on horseback carrying & American flag
    Printer: Woman's Land Army of America
    Condition: Minor tears along the bottom edge
  - Patriotic League, undated; WWI-97; 71cm / 51cm multicolor (mostly red, white, blue) (Map-case 52)
    Type: Patriotic League
    Description: Woman standing with an American flag
    Printer: U.S. Prtg. & Lith. Co., NY
    Condition: Minor damage along the right edge
  - Spirit of America – JOIN, 1919; WWI-98; 76.5cm / 50.5cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Red Cross nurse holding an American flag, Red Cross in the foreground
    Printer: American Red Cross
    Condition: minor damage around the edges
  - US Marines Want You – Apply At 562 Broadway, Albany, NY, undated; WWI-99; 72cm / 53cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Marine pointing outward
  - Fourth Liberty Loan, Six Billion Dollars, The Town of Cazenovia is asked for..., undated; WWI-100; 76cm / 51cm black, white (Map-case 52)
    Type: Fourth Liberty Loan
    Condition: Major damage around all edges
  - [Marine Corps], undated; WWI-131; 66cm / 45.7cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: Marine Corps
    Description: Two marines flanking a pillar; on top of the pillar are a globe, anchor and eagle and the banner "Semper Fi"
    Condition: Very good
  - Clear the Way!! / Buy Bonds / Fourth Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-132; 75cm / 49cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Group of men operating field cannon, surmounted by woman in white wrapped in American flag
    Printer: Niagara Litho, Buffalo, New York
  - Remember! / The flag of liberty / Support it ! / Buy / U.S. Government Bonds / 3rd Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-133; may be another copy of WWI-30, above; 76 cm / 51 cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Description: Group of men and women, American flag behind them
  - We Need You! / Coast Artillery Corps USA, undated; WWI-134; 63.5 cm / 94cm red, black, green, white (Map-case 52)
    Description: silhouette of group of men with field cannon
    Artist: Tolson
    Printer: Rode & Brand Litho. N.Y.C.
- World War I, Onondaga County
  - Let your money help our boys over there win the war, undated; WWI-101; 111cm / 72cm red, white, blue (Map-case 103)
    Type: War chest
    Description: words only, no illustration
  - The world must be made safe for democracy -- Wilson / Fight or give, undated; WWI-102; 109cm / 71cm red, white blue (Map-case 103)
  - Fill the war chest for all war relief, undated; WWI-103; 108cm / 72cm red, white, blue (Map-case 103)
    Description: illustration of open chest of money
    Printer: Cornell Show Printing, Syracuse, NY
    Condition: lower left corner missing
  - Ready! Stop! Give! General Pershing cables: 'No other organization sine the world began has ever done such great contructive work with the efficiency, dispatch, and understanding, often under adverse circumstances, than has been done in France by the American Red Cross in the last six months' Syracuse and Onondaga County War Chest, undated; WWI-104; 98cm / 65cm red, white, black (Map-case 103)
    Description: Black silhouette of soldier, presumably Pershing, overlaid with words from his cable
    Condition: small tear at center of top edge
  - Wanted - 100 graduate nurses / we need you / Syracuse Chapter American Red Cross is called upon to enroll 100 nurses at once! Your country needs you!, undated; WWI-105; 103cm / 79cm red, white, black (Map-case 103)
    Description: Red Cross nurse standing with arm around young woman, gesturing to wounded soldier lying in bed with another Red Cross nurse bending over him
    Condition:
  - U.S. Marines active service on land and sea / Enlist at 214 East Fayette Street Syracuse, undated; WWI-106; 101cm / 70cm multi (Map-case 103)
    Description: Marine in dress uniform, marching, with shipyard and buildings in background
    Condition: 3" tear at bottom edge
  - Give! Syracuse and Onondaga County war chest / They fight for you / Protect them / Help the Red Cross raise $100,000,000 at once, undated; WWI-107; 103cm / 68cm red, orange, brown, black, white (Map-case 103)
    Type: American Red Cross / war chest
    Description: Statue of Liberty, overlaid with large Red Cross symbol in white circle, wounded soldier on battlefield reaching out his hand
    Artist: W.G. Sesser
  - Help fill the war chest / Canastota War Chest Association Incorporated, undated; WWI-108; 108cm / 72cm orange (possibly originally red), white, black (Map-case 104)
    Description: open chest of money
    Condition: lower right edge tattered
  - The world must be made safe for democracy - Pres. Wilson / Help fill the war chest / Fight or give, undated; WWI-109; 109cm / 71cm red, white, black (Map-case 104)
    Description: line drawing of rather goofy-looking man in top hat, pointing to open chest of money
  - Help fill the war chest / Rome War Chest Association, undated; WWI-110; 108cm / 71cm red, white, black (Map-case 104)
    Condition: two large tears at top edge
  - Help fill the war chest for all war relief, undated; WWI-111; 108cm / 71cm red, white, blue (Map-case 104)
    Description: open chest of money, soldier standing guard
    Condition: lower right corner missing, large tear at top edge
  - Help fill the war chest for all our boys, undated; WWI-112; 109cm / 71cm red, white, blue (Map-case 104)
    Description: chest of coins
    Condition: puncture tear in upper center
  - Help / Syracuse War Chest / Your American Red Cross / Wanted! 50,000 member $600,000 / Enroll to-day headquarters Onondaga Hotel / Syracuse War Chest, undated; WWI-113; 119cm / 76cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Type: American Red Cross / War chest
    Description: scene with nurse, ambulance, wounded soldier lying on stretcher, explosion in background
    Printer: The Schilling Press, Inc.
  - HALT! Who goes there? Where? Anywhere! On land or sea or in the air you'll find Uncle Sam's marines THEY GO FIRST Apply for enlistment at U.S. Marine Corps Recruiting Station 214 East Fayette Street - - Syracuse N.Y., undated; WWI-114; 101cm / 76cm red, white, black (Map-case 105)
    Description: engraved illustrations of various military scenes, six small down the left side and one large across the top
    Artist: Axel Tornrose
  - Join the Air Service and serve in France / Do it now / Apply to Aviation Examining Board Syracuse Free Dispensary, 1917; WWI-115; 106cm / 63cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Type: Air Service
    Description: scene with biplane (Sopwith Camel?) flying through cloud, two soldiers on the ground, one with binoculars
  - Syracuse and Onondaga Co. War Chest, undated; WWI-116; 2 copies 61cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Type: American Red Cross / War Chest
    Description: colored (chalk or pencil?) portrait of Red Cross nurse, arms outstretched towards the viewer, soldiers marching with flag behind her, all on medium green background
    Artist: Harrison Fisher
  - Back Up the Boys to the Limit! / Syracuse War Chest Onondaga County, undated; WWI-117; 61cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 105)
  - Help fill it to the brim! / Syracuse War Chest Onondaga County, undated; WWI-118; 61cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Condition: small tear on bottom edge
  - In the Name of Mercy = Give! / Syracuse War Chest Onondaga County, undated; WWI-119; 61cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Condition: faint black smudging across top, may have been result of printing process
  - Don't wait to be asked = Give! Give! Give! / Syracuse War Chest Onondaga County, undated; WWI-120; 61cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Condition: small tear at top right edge
  - It must be filled! You must help! / Syracuse War Chest Onondaga County, undated; WWI-121; 61cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 105)
    Condition: crease down left margin
  - For active service join the U. S. Marines / For full information apply at 214 East Fayette Street, Syracuse N. Y., undated; WWI-122; 66cm / 46cm multi (Map-case 106)
    Type: U. S. Marines
    Description: marine raising flag, second marine saluting, background shows beach with palm trees and Navy ships in the distance
  - Are you back of these boys? / Loyalty to one means loyalty to both / Syracuse and Onondaga Co. War Chest, undated; WWI-123; 61cm / 46cm red, white, blue, brown (Map-case 106)
    Description: Two soldiers, one carrying American flag, the other with Red Cross armband carrying Red Cross flag
    Condition: small part of lower right corner stripped
  - U.S. Marines serve American on land and sea / Enlist at 214 East Fayette St., Syracuse, undated; WWI-124; 55cm / 35cm multi (Map-case 106)
    Description: Marine in dress uniform, marching, with shipyard and buildings in background (smaller version of WWI-106)
    Condition: several horizontal creases
  - Help fill the war chest for our boys, undated; WWI-125; 53cm / 35cm red, white, blue (Map-case 106)
    Description: open chest of coins
    Condition: 1" tear at top edge
  - Help the Red Cross / Syracuse and Onondaga Co. War Chest, undated; WWI-126 (Map-case 106)
    Description: Red Cross nurse supporting wounded soldier with her right arm, left arm outstretched towards viewer
    Artist: Herman Roeg
  - He did his duty / "No finer military organization than the Marine Corps exists in the world." George Dewey Admiral of the Navy / Will you? Join for active service land and sea U.S. Marines / Apply at 214 East Fayette Street, Syracuse, undated; WWI-127; 71cm / 55cm black and white (Map-case 106)
    Description: pen and ink portrait of Dewey, below the quote the name "George Dewey" appears in his handwriting (his signature)
    Artist: initials PW at lower right
  - Help take care of our boys "over here" and "over there" / [lengthy quotes from Gov. Charles S. Whitman and Pres. Woodrow Wilson] / Syracuse and Onondaga County War Chest, 1917; WWI-128; 72cm / 53cm red, white, blue (Map-case 106)
    Description: chest of money in red box at upper left, Whitman quotes in red box at upper right; in center large male figure in suit with arms outstretched over a building with "Knights of Columbus Everybody Welcome" sign, various people, buildings, cars, etc.
    Artist: central image "copyright by L. H. Rankin Co. 1917"
    Printer: Cornell Show Printing, 561 S. Clinton St., Syracuse N.Y.
  - The Navy is Calling / Enlist Now / U.S. Navy Recruiting Station McCarthy Building Syracuse, 1917; WWI-129; 104cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 106)
    Type: Recruiting
    Description: American eagle facing off left,with red, white and blue shield on breast, wings mantling five small figures of sailors with bayonets, words along the bottom
    Artist: L.N. Britton
    Printer: unknown
    Condition: several open tears on top and bottom edge, several at top have tape scars
  - Help / Deliver / the / Goods / Do It Now / U.S. Navy Recruiting Station / McCarthy Building Syracuse, 1917; WWI-130; 104cm / 71cm multicolor (Map-case 106)
    Description: smiling sailor hoisting very large shells, labeled with tag "To be delivered RUSH" with navy ship and naval guns in background
    Condition: several open edge tears, left edge ragged and worn
- World War II
  - China Defense League, undated; WWII-1; 79cm / 51.5cm brown, white (Map-case 53)
    Type: China Defense League
    Description: Soldier holding bayonet
    Artist: Ping Hung
    Condition: Hole in center, some tears along edges
  - Aggression Made Them Homeless / The China Defense League Rehabilitates Refugees, undated; WWII-2; 55cm / 67cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Type: Chinese Defense League
    Description: Chinese family homeless in a field
    Condition: very damaged in the center along crease
  - Thin Khaki Line Keeps The Fate of Belgium from Your Hearth & Horn / Get Into Khaki Now!, undated; WWII-3; 53.5cm / 71cm red, white, blue, black (Map-case 53)
    Type: Canadian Recruiting Division
    Description: Outline of soldier on the battlefield
    Printer: Central Recruiting Committee, No. 2 Military Division, Toronto
  - French Relief Fund, Inc. / A Member of the National War Fund, undated; WWII-4; 104cm / 68.5cm brown, red, white, blue (Map-case 53)
    Type: National War Fund, French Relief Fund, Inc.
    Description: Soldier calling to another in front of French, American, & British flags
    Artist: Louis Fernez
    Condition: Some tears and missing sections along the top and bottom edges
  - Jap... Your Next! We'll Finish the Job! / US Army Official Poster, 9/6/1944; WWII-5; 101.5cm / 70 cm red, white, blue (Map-case 53)
    Description: Uncle Sam about the throw a wrench
    Condition: Small tears around edges, large tear on top edge
  - 7th War Loan Now "All Together", 1945; WWII-6; 66cm / 46.5cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Type: U.S. Treasury Department
    Description: US Marines at Iwo Jima
    Artist: C. C. Beall
    Printer: US Government Printing Office
  - My Daddy Bought Me A Government Bond, undated; WWII-7; 1932 multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Description: Child with war bond
    Artist: ---
    Printer: U.S. Printing & Lithographic Co., NY
  - British Bombers have carried out over 1,600 raids on Germany / (Up to May 1941), undated; WWII-8; 39cm / 51.5cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Type: British Propaganda Poster
    Description: British Bombers
  - Battleships of the Royal Navy, steaming in line ahead, undated; WWII-9; 39cm / 51.5cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Description: Battleships
  - One of the Magnificent British Fighters which have shot down over 3,000 German Planes, undated; WWII-10; 39cm / 51.5cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Description: British Fighter
    Artist: Roland Davies
  - A Battery of Britain's giant coastal defense guns mounted on railway trucks, undated; WWII-11; 39cm / 51.5cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Description: Gun mounted on a truck
  - A British Anti-aircraft Battery in action. More than 590 German raiders have been destroyed by anti-aircraft fire over Britain., undated; WWII-12; 39cm / 51.5cm multicolor (Map-case 53)
    Description: British Anti-aircraft Battery
    Artist: James Gardner
  - Beat "Firebomb Fritz" – Britain Shall Not Burn - Britain's Fireguard is Britain's Defense, undated; WWII-13; 76cm / 51cm red, white, blue, black (Map-case 53)
    Type: Firebombs
    Description: "Firebomb Fritz" shooting through the sky
    Artist: Ministry of Home Security